Guide to William and Sally Rhoads Collection of Elverhoj, 1887-1985 (bulk 1901-1942)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series III. Letters and Financial Records, 1914-1942, 1985
  - Letter from Roosevelt, Eleanor to Anders H. Anderson, 1935 Aug 6; [Typewritten, signed, stamped "Newburgh Historical Society."] (Folder 1.42)
    On White House stationery. "I am sorry this avenue seems to be closed. I have written to Miss Flanagan of the Federal Emergency Relief, and as soon as I hear from her, I will let you know."
  - Letter from Zelner, Eleanor Lewis to Helen Gearn (Newburgh Historical Society), regarding Captain Sears and Elverhoj, 1985 Feb 19; [Typewritten, signed, stamped "Newburgh Historical Society."] (Folder 1.43)
  - Miscellaneous receipts and invoices, 1915-1916 (Folder 1.44)
  - The Volund Crafts Shop, receipt, 1914 Oct 24 (Folder 1.45)
  - W. H. Townsend, Jr., receipts, 1915-1916 (Folder 1.46)
- Series IV. Printed Images and Ephemera, 1887-1937
  - Announcements
    - "Elverhoj Art Colony. Your Summer Study Your Vacation and Your Week-End Outing and Theatre,", 1925 (Folder 1.47)
    - Elverhoj auction notice, 1937 Sep; [19 in x 25 in] (Folder 6.8 (Oversize))
    - "Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen. Summer Season - June 15 - Sept 15,", [1918] (Folder 1.47)
    - "The Elverhoj Theatre and Moorish Terrace at Elverhoj Park, Milton-on-Hudson, New York,", [1930] (Folder 1.47)
    - The Elverhoj Theatre, "Pluck a Rose," 1931 season announcement (Folder 1.47)
    - "A Summer School of Art and Handicrafts on the Hudson. Elverhoj...,", 1914 (Folder 1.47)
  - Clippings
    - "Det Gamle Æbletree" by K. G. Ossiannilsson, undated (Folder 2.2)
    - Pottery and craftsmanship, undated (Folder 1.48)
  - Envelopes
    - "Elverhoj Colony of Artists and Craftsmen, Milton-on-Hudson, NY,", undated; [5 envelopes] (Folder 1.49)
  - Invitations
    - Exhibition opening, "Hudson River Exhibition of Paintings and Handicrafts,", 1912 Nov 21 (Folder 1.50)
    - Exhibition opening, "Third Annual Exhibition of Fine and Applied Art at Elverhoj, 1914 Sep 16 (Folder 1.50)
  - Pamphlets
    - "Elverhoj - The Place of the Arts in the Country,", circa 1930; [2 copies] (Folder 1.51)
    - "Elverhoj Lectures,", circa 1915 (Folder 1.51)
    - "The Half Moon. Cornwall-on-Hudson, New York,", undated (Folder 1.51)
    - Madsen, Emil Ferdinand, "Vore Fædres Kirke - Jubilæums Kantate," with illustrations by A. H. Andersen, 1901 (Folder 1.52)
    - "The Zodiac," The Zodiac Artist Colony, circa 1912 (Folder 1.53)
  - Printed Bookplates and Cards
    - Andersen, A. H., Crescent moon with woman holding brushes and palette and smaller man with brush and paintings, undated (Folder 1.54)
    - Andersen, A. H., Geometric and floral design around small building with sign "Furniture and Undertaking,", undated (Folder 1.54)
    - Unknown artist, "Diakonisse-Sagens Vugge,", undated (Folder 1.55)
    - Unknown artist, "EX LIBRIS EDITH M. CHAPMAN,", undated (Folder 1.55)
    - Unknown artist, "EX LIBRIS EDWARD HARVEY,", undated (Folder 1.55)
    - Unknown artist, "Greetings from Orchard Beach,", undated; [2 copies] (Folder 1.55)
  - Printed Illustrations
    - Anderson, [?], "Nobody Loves Me,", 1905 (Folder 1.56)
    - Corbould, H., "Thou thinkst thy children's laughing play...," Winter's Wreath, undated (Folder 1.57)
    - Dekorative Vorbilder 26, Jul. Hoffman, Stuttgart, undated; [23 leaves] (Folder 4.11)
    - Four illustrations on one card: James Scott, Roy Hutchinson, Gleason, and [?] Jensen, undated (Folder 1.58)
    - "K. W. Diefenbach: Per Aspera Ad Astra," No. 420, 424, and 426, undated (Folder 2.3)
    - "Old Friend I dream again…" Rembrandt Art Co., St. Paul, 1909 (Folder 1.58)
    - Sargent, [?], "Prophets,", 1887, 1898; [3 leaves] (Folder 4.12)
    - Scandinavian artists, various prints, 1891-1914, undated; [15 leaves] (Folder 4.13)
    - "Tick! Tick! Tick!," Frank Leslie's Lady's Magazine, undated (Folder 1.58)
    - Unidentified illustrations, undated; [2 prints] (Folder 1.58)
  - Programs
    - "Einar Cajanus," Elverhoj Auditorium, 1924 Aug 18 (Folder 1.59)
    - The Elverhoj Theatre, 1929 Jun 24-29 (Folder 1.60)
    - The Elverhoj Theatre, 1929 Jul 8-13 (Folder 1.60)
    - The Elverhoj Theatre, 1929 Jul 22-27 (Folder 1.60)
    - The Elverhoj Theatre, 1929 Jul 29 - Aug 3 (Folder 1.60)
    - The Elverhoj Theatre, 1929 Aug 5-10; [2 copies] (Folder 1.60)
    - "Elverhoj Theatre, Summer Season 1930, Opening Week,", 1930 Jun 17 (Folder 1.61)
    - The Elverhoj Theatre, "Genius in Love,", 1934 Jun 18; [2 copies] (Folder 1.61)
    - The Elverhoj Theatre, "Gram,", 1934 Jun 25 (Folder 1.61)
    - University Players. "Up Pops The Devil." Dinners in the Elverhoj Tavern., [1933] (Folder 1.62)
    - University Players. "Meet The Wife,", [1933] Jul 5 (Folder 1.62)
    - University Players. "Desperate Lady,", [1933] Jul 12 (Folder 1.62)
- Series V. Publications, 1912-1941
  - Arts & Decoration, 1916 Aug (Folder 2.4)
  - The Craftsman, 1913 Jun (Folder 2.5)
  - The Craftsman, 1914 May (Folder 2.6)
  - The Craftsman, 1914 Jun (Folder 2.7)
  - The Craftsman, 1915 Mar (Folder 2.8)
  - The Craftsman, 1915 May (Folder 2.9)
  - The Craftsman, 1916 Apr (Folder 2.10)
  - The Craftsman, 1916 Jun (Folder 2.11)
  - Jule Roser, 1914; [cover and first 2 pages] (Folder 4.14)
  - KipiKawi, 1912 (Folder 3.1)
  - Midvinter, Vol. 16, 1913 (Folder 4.15)
  - The Print-Collector's Quarterly, 1912 Feb (Folder 3.2)
  - Teubners Englisches Unterrichtswerk, 1941 (Folder 3.3)
  - The Touchstone, Vol. 5 No. 3, 1919 Jun (Folder 3.4)
  - The Touchstone, Vol. 5 No. 6, 1919 Sep (Folder 3.5)
- Series VI. Silverware, undated
  - Six silver teaspoons, all marked "ELVERHOJ,", undated (Box 5)